[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "Concerning ER",
    "options": [
      "connection between nuclear membrane and nucleus",
      "nuclear membrane and cell membrane",
      "formed from compact structures",
      "formed from tubular microsomal structures",
      "B and D"
    ],
    "answer": ["B and D"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["cell physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "The following are examples of integral protein except",
    "options": [
      "cell adhesion protein",
      "antigen",
      "channel protein",
      "none of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["none of the above"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["cell physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "The process of engulfing solvents or fluid's is known as",
    "options": ["phagocytosis", "pinocytosis", "osmosis", "diffusion"],
    "answer": ["pinocytosis"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["cell physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "Which best describes homeostasis",
    "options": [
      "fluctuation with homeostatic range",
      "maintenance of constant body temperature",
      "dynamic equilibrium",
      "changing environment",
      "none of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["dynamic equilibrium"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["cell physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "Transportation of a molecule across membrane with the help of protein is called",
    "options": [
      "simple diffusion",
      "facilitated diffusion",
      "carrier-mediated diffusion",
      "active diffusion"
    ],
    "answer": ["facilitated diffusion"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["cell physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Which system is least involved in homeostasis",
    "options": ["integumentary", "reproductive", "CVS", "endocrine"],
    "answer": ["reproductive"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["cell physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "A cell must expend energy to transport substances using",
    "options": [
      "cell membrane pumps",
      "facilitated diffusion",
      "ion channels",
      "osmosis",
      "simple diffusion"
    ],
    "answer": ["cell membrane pumps"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["cell physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "The two body system that regulate homeostasis are the",
    "options": [
      "CVS and endocrine",
      "reproductive and endocrine",
      "integumentary and nervous",
      "nervous and endocrine"
    ],
    "answer": ["nervous and endocrine"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["cell physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "The following points about microfilament are true except",
    "options": [
      "they form cytoskeleton with microtubules",
      "this provide support and shape",
      "they form intracellular conducting channels",
      "they are part of the cell"
    ],
    "answer": ["they form intracellular conducting channels"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["cell physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Which of the following is not true of the nuclear envelope",
    "options": [
      "The nuclear envelope is exactly like other cellular membranes",
      "The nuclear envelope separates the genetic material from the cytoplasm",
      "The nuclear envelope is a pair of concrete membranes",
      "The nuclear envelope is studded with pores",
      "all of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["The nuclear envelope is a pair of concrete membranes"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["cell physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "Which of the following correctly lists the levels of organization from least complex to most complex",
    "options": [
      "cellular,tissue, chemical system, organ, organism",
      "chemical, cellular, tissue, organ,system,organism",
      "tissue, cellular,chemical, organ, system, organism",
      "chemical, tissue, system , organ,organism"
    ],
    "answer": ["chemical, cellular, tissue, organ,system,organism"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["cell physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "Non-membrane bound organelle include the following except",
    "options": ["ribosome", "centrioles", "cytoplasm", "cytoskeleton"],
    "answer": ["cytoplasm"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["cell physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "Membrane bound organelle include the following except",
    "options": ["mitochondria", "nucleus", "ribosome", "golgi apparatus"],
    "answer": ["ribosome"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["cell physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "The cell organelle which consist of membranous saccules called cisternae is called",
    "options": ["mitochondria", "peroxisomes", "lysosomes", "golgi apparatus"],
    "answer": ["golgi apparatus"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["cell physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "The type of bulk transport that involves the transport of substances from high hydrostatic pressure to low hydrostatic pressure is",
    "options": [
      "phagocytosis",
      "pinocytosis",
      "filtration",
      "vesicular transport"
    ],
    "answer": ["filtration"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["cell physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "The process by which macromolecules are absorbed into the cell interior is called",
    "options": [
      "phagocytosis",
      "pinocytosis",
      "filtration",
      "facilitated diffusion"
    ],
    "answer": ["pinocytosis"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["cell physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "Which of these in the extracellular matrix does the cell membrane bind to?",
    "options": [
      "chondroitin sulfate",
      "heparin sulfate",
      "fibronectin",
      "hyaluronic acid",
      "none of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["fibronectin"],
    "explanation": "cell membrane bind fibronectin and laminin in the extracellular matrix",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["cell physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "Which of the cell organelle is used for the formation of basal bodies",
    "options": ["lysosomes", "peroxisomes", "centrioles", "cytoskeleton"],
    "answer": ["centrioles"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["cell physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "Which of the cell organelle contains membranous sacs called cristae",
    "options": ["centriole", "golgi apparatus", "mitochondria", "peroxisomes"],
    "answer": ["mitochondria"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["cell physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "Genetic information of nuclear DNA is transmitted to the site of protein synthesis by",
    "options": ["rRNA", "mRNA", "tRNA", "polysomes"],
    "answer": ["mRNA"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["cell physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "The following are features of sympathetic discharge reactions except",
    "options": [
      "muscle vasculature dilates",
      "increase in GIT motility",
      "increase in BMR",
      "increase HR"
    ],
    "answer": ["increase in GIT motility"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["ANS"]
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "Which of the following is not correct ?",
    "options": [
      "all preganglionic neuron secrete acetylcholine",
      "all postganglionic parasympathetic neuron secrete acetylcholine",
      "all postganglionic sympathetic neuron secrete noradrenaline",
      "all postganglionic parasympathetic neuron are short",
      "all preganglionic sympathetic neuron are short"
    ],
    "answer": ["all postganglionic sympathetic neuron secrete noradrenaline"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["ANS"]
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "SLUDD responses will not include",
    "options": ["lacrimation", "tachycardia", "salivation", "urination"],
    "answer": ["tachycardia"],
    "explanation": "SLUDGE:  Salivate, lacrimate, urinate, defecate, gastrointestinal effects, emesis (vomiting) and bradycardia",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["ANS"]
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "The nerve cell contains the following except",
    "options": [
      "nissl granules",
      "centrosome",
      "mitochondria",
      "golgi body",
      "none of these"
    ],
    "answer": ["centrosome"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["ANS"]
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "The white colour of the myelinated nerve fibre is produced by",
    "options": [
      "saltatory cells",
      "secretory cells",
      "myelin sheath",
      "schwann cells",
      "axon"
    ],
    "answer": ["myelin sheath"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["muscle physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "The ability of nerve fibre to transmit impulse from the area of stimulation to other area known as",
    "options": [
      "conductivity",
      "action potential",
      "salutatory conduction",
      "summation",
      "adaptation"
    ],
    "answer": ["conductivity"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["muscle physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "All of the following are true of skeletal muscles except",
    "options": [
      "they are voluntary",
      "they are branched",
      "they are striated",
      "they are mononucleated",
      "none of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["they are mononucleated"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["muscle physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "All of the following are true of cardiac muscles except",
    "options": [
      "they are involuntary",
      "they are unbranched",
      "they are striated",
      "they are mononucleated",
      "none of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["they are unbranched"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["muscle physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "All of the following are true of smooth muscles except",
    "options": [
      "they are spindle-shaped",
      "they are unbranched",
      "they lack cross striations",
      "they are involuntary",
      "none of these"
    ],
    "answer": ["none of these"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["muscle physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "The following are supplied by the autonomic nervous system except",
    "options": [
      "skeletal system",
      "cardiac muscle",
      "smooth muscle",
      "all of these",
      "none of these"
    ],
    "answer": ["skeletal system"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["muscle physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "question": "Which of the following is not part of the actin filament?",
    "options": [
      "actin",
      "myosin",
      "tropomyosin",
      "troponin",
      "none of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["myosin"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["muscle physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "question": "Active site of F-actin molecule is covered by",
    "options": [
      "troponin",
      "tropomyosin",
      "troponin T",
      "troponin C",
      "all of the above"
    ],
    "answer": ["tropomyosin"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["muscle physiology"]
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "question": "Each myosin head has two attachment sites; one site is for actin while the other is for",
    "options": [
      "Calcium ion",
      "ATP molecule",
      "troponin T",
      "all of these",
      "none of these"
    ],
    "answer": ["ATP molecule"],
    "explanation": "",
    "subcourse": ["TOPIC BY TOPIC"],
    "course": "PHYSIOLOGY",
    "topics": ["muscle physiology"]
  }
]
